Contact

+905325696135 (Mobile) ozguremreozturk@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ ozguremreozturk (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

International Trade
Business Development
International Business

Languages

Turkish (Native or Bilingual) English (Full Professional) French (Full Professional)

Publications

Dış Ticaretin Dünü Bugünü

Ozgur Emre Ozturk

International Sales Director at IT Porter Technology / FMSS Global / Fintech / Microfinance / MFI

Bağlarbaşı Mah., İstanbul Province, Turkey

Summary

I'm a foreign trade and international sales expert. I'm working in the field of international trade as an exporter and importer for several years and had strong background on Foreign Trade and Supply Chain Management full of practice and experiences.

I have practiced import, export, logistics, warehouse management, transit trade, qc, free zone legistations and custom brokers management during my all career.

I am looking forward to meet, exchange insights and experiences and looking for new business opportunities.

Don't hesitate to contact me for any feedback.

Specialities: Foreign Trade, International Marketing, International Trade Terms, Consulting, Marketing, FMCG,

Experience

IT Porter Technology International Sales Director November 2019 - Present Istanbul, Turkey

International Business Development for IT Porter Technology.

IT Porter Technology provides Digital Banking Solutions on Cloud or on Site for your instutions.

IT Porter Technology is one of the very important technology companies of Turkey, providing Core Banking System, infrastructure solutions, payment solutions, international money transfer systems to the banks and microfinances.

While entering to ZONEPESA with your PESAPORT, which are an IT Porter projects designed for Sub-Saharan Africa and LATAM, your instutions will have the most easy way to reach to the local and global market and customers.

My responsabilities are as follows::

Develop, review, gain agreement for and implement the export sales strategy to achieve targeted growth.

Take responsibility for the sales and profit growth of product ranges overseas markets and the achievement of export sales targets.

Negotiate representation agreements and sales contracts in line with company policy which will fully meet the needs of both the company sales budget.

Research and evaluate new market opportunities especially in Africa.

Research and report on business opportunities, market conditions, product development opportunities and competitor activities including a monthly report on activity, achievements, opportunities and points of interest.

Develop Country based branches and local agencies in Rwanda, Uganda, South Sudan, Tanzania, DRC, Cameroon, Ivory Coast, Guinea, Senegal, Mauritania.

Starting to develop new agencies in Kenya, South Africa, Mali, Algeria, Morocco, Tunisia, Egypt soon.

#corebanking #banking #software #iot #ai #microfinance #microcredit #mfi #mfb #blockchain #sacco #bceao #umeao #udeac #cemac #islamicfinance #français #french

7URIX

International Sales Director
July 2019 - November 2019 (5 months)

Istanbul, Turkey

International Sales and Marketing for USA/Turkey Joint Venture Start Up Zurix.

Zurix provides Core Banking System, payment solutions, international money transfer systems to the banks and microfinances.

My responsabilities are as follows::

Develop, review, gain agreement for and implement the export sales strategy to achieve targeted growth.

Take responsibility for the sales and profit growth of product ranges overseas markets and the achievement of export sales targets.

Negotiate representation agreements and sales contracts in line with company policy which will fully meet the needs of both the company sales budget.

Research and evaluate new market opportunities especially in Africa.

Research and report on business opportunities, market conditions, product development opportunities and competitor activities including a monthly report on activity, achievements, opportunities and points of interest.

#corebanking #banking #software #iot #ai #microfinance #microcredit #mfi #mfb #blockchain #sacco #bceao #umeao #udeac #cemac #islamicfinance #français #french

Ozden Group of Companies Export Development Manager May 2019 - July 2019 (3 months) Ankara, Turkey

As being responsible for Turkey's leading Shoe Care Product "Smart", my responsabilities are as follows:

Develop, review, gain agreement for and implement the export sales strategy to achieve targeted growth.

Take responsibility for the sales and profit growth of product ranges overseas markets and the achievement of export sales targets.

Negotiate representation agreements and sales contracts in line with company policy which will fully meet the needs of both the company sales budget Research and evaluate new market opportunities and draw up written proposals to the MD.

Research and report on business opportunities, market conditions, product development opportunities and competitor activities including a monthly report on activity, achievements, opportunities and points of interest.

Statera Foreign Trade Founder March 2016 - April 2019 (3 years 2 months) Istanbul, Turkey

Family owned foreign trade business, mostly e-trade.

Being as Co-Founder and Coordinator of Statera in Turkey, my duty is to control sales and business channels for the company in EMEA region including Turkey.

With my core competencies on foreign trade and supply chain management, I organize new sales and distribution channels for my group, within Turkey, Middle East and Europe.

Some of my core competencies are as follows;

- *B2B and B2C experience
- *Transit Trade experience
- *Good Knowledge of trade from/to the following areas: Fareast, Europe, CIS Countries, Africa, Middle East.
- *Good Knowledge of Hardware Materials, especially Screws, Bolts, Nuts, Washers, Insect Screen, Fiberglass Mesh Wall Net, Tapes, Silicones.
 *Good Knowledge of Chemical Materials for the insecticide production including Prallethrin, PBO, Pyrethrum, Mat Heaters, Mat Tablets, D-Tetramethrin, etc.
- *Good Knowledge of Wood Species, Wood Window Production.
- *Good Knowledge of China, India, CIS, Europe markets.
- *Fluent English, French, Turkish and Beginner Chinese, German.

DNG Yağmur Yapı ve Bağlantı Elemanları Foreign Trade Manager March 2016 - April 2019 (3 years 2 months) Istanbul, Turkey

DNG Yağmur Yapı is a part of Turkish Company Group located in Turkey's heartbeat trade areas, Istanbul. DNG Yağmur Yapı serves not only quality products but also wide range related and customs products with fast delivery and high quality into the regions it serves.

DNG Yağmur Yapı with its group of companies is one of the largest fastener manufacturer, importer and trader in Turkey with its capacity of 300 MT/month production and 150 MT/month import.

Product Range:

- Stainless Steel Screws / Security Screws and Fasteners / Inox / A2 304 / A4
- 316
- Self Drilling Screws / Roofing Screws / uPVC Window Screws / Drywall Screws / Chipboard Screws / Self Tapping Screws / Concrete Screws
- Bolts / Nuts / Anchors
- Fiberglass Insect Screen / Pleated Screen
- Fiberglass Mesh / Fiberglass Self Adhesive Tape
- PVC Ceiling Panel / Led Ceiling Panel
- PU Foam / Silicone / Chemical Anchor

Selectron Elektrokimya

Foreign Trade Manager

November 2010 - March 2016 (5 years 5 months)

Istanbul, Turkey

Being as the foreign trade chief/manager of the leading foreign trade group of Turkey in the area of Hardware, Chemical and Wooden Windows and doors

- * Experience of import as 60 Containers/month and 15 trucks/month.
- * Experience of export and transit trade as 10 containers/month and 5 trucks/months.
- * Ability to handle 50 million USD trade capacity/year.

Kareli Defter Training and Consulting

Foreign Trade Counsellor

February 2008 - March 2010 (2 years 2 months)

Organizing of Foreign Trade Training and Consultancy services for companies Setting new business and sales channels

Providing tools for Corporate Training and Consultancy services

E-Business / E-Marketing Project Management.

Social media entegration of corporate website

MMI Turkiye

Customer Relations and Sales Controller

March 2007 - February 2008 (1 year)

Sales and organizing of Corporate Training and Consultancy services Setting new business and sales channels Sales and organizing Open Training Programs

Open Training Programs that I have organised:

- Wake up Marketing Leader inside You! (w/ Vestel Executive Committee Member Levent Hatay)
- o E-mail Marketing Workshop (w/ Project House Agency Chairman Cüneyt Özdemir)
- o WOMM Word of Mouth Marketing (w/ Turkcell WOMM Team Leader Alper Akcan)
- o Search Engine Marketing Conference w/ Google main sponsorship (w/ 100 participants)
- Mobile Marketing Lab w/ Ericsson and Turkcell sponsorship
 (w/ 300 participants)

Academy Intrade Foreign Trade Consultancy

Founder Partner

November 2004 - March 2007 (2 years 5 months)

- Sales and organizing of Foreign Trade Training and Consultancy services for companies
- · Setting new business and sales channels
- Setting Training Advisor and Direct Sales Teams
- Setting sales projects and determine sales targets
- Organization of 21 certificate programs across Turkey w/1050 participants targeting exceptionally Adana, Kayseri, İzmir, Ankara, Gaziantep which are leading industrial cities of Turkey.

English Time Language Schools & Overseas Education Branch Manager

March 2001 - October 2004 (3 years 8 months)

Increasing student number from 400 to 850 compared to previous semester Increasing sales from 125.000 TL to 360.000 TL compared to previous semester

Preparing customer satisfaction tests

Following the test results, providing extra activity hours to the students. Reaching to the maximum level of students of branch history.

Alfa Airlines

Steward

December 1999 - December 2000 (1 year 1 month)

Education

Frankfurt School of Finance & Management Islamic Microfinance · (2019 - 2020)

Anadolu Üniversitesi BS, Business Administration · (2003 - 2008)

Akdeniz Üniversitesi BS, Tourism · (1997 - 2001)

Saint Benoit French College (1989 - 1997)